Guide to the Martin Wong Papers MSS.102
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V: Video & Sound recordings, 1989-1993; .4 Linear Feet in one manuscript box; 3 videocassettes; 1 audiocassette
  Series V: Audio and Videocassettes is comprised of 3 videocassette recordings and an audiocassette. Topics include Wong's "Chinatown" paintings and NEA funding.
  - Video: "1991 New Year's", ID: 102.0001 (Box 7b, Media ID: 102.0001, Case 102.0001)
    Currently available.
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Access DVD available.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Duration: 2 hours
    Original format: VHS
  - Video: "Keith Haring", undated; ID: 102.0002 (Box 7b, Media ID: 102.0002, Case 102.0002)
    Duration: 34 minutes
  - Video: Martin Wong, "People Are Talking": Topic: NEA Funding (WOR TV, Ch. 9), August 8, 1989; ID: 102.0003 (Box 7b, Media ID: 102.0003, Case 102.0003)
  - Audio: "Martin Wong: The Chinatown Paintings" (KBLX 102.9 FM/1400 AM), October 7, 1993; ID: 102.0004 (Box 7b, Media ID: 102.0004, Case 102.0004)
    Currently unavailable until duplication occurs.
    Access CD available.
    Duration: 2 minutes
    Original format: 1/4" audiocassette
- Series VI: Photography, 1982-1999; 2.5 Linear Feet in 12 box binders and one flat oversize box
  Series VI: Photography is comprised of hundreds of snapshots, most of which constitute source material for Wong's art. The series is ordered by theme: photos of Wong, photos of Wong's work, and source photos of people, cityscapes and urban life, cars and motorbikes, men in uniform, works of art and museum pieces, birds and beasts, Chinatown and Chinese imagery, and various miscellaneous source snapshots.
  - Photos of Martin Wong, undated (Box 15*)
  - Photos of Wong's Work, undated (Box 15*)
  - Source Photos: Cityscapes & Urban Life, undated (Box 15A*)
  - Source Photos: Cityscapes & Urban Life, undated (Box 16*)
  - Source Photos: Cityscapes & Urban Life, undated (Box 16A*)
  - Source Photos: Birds & Beasts, undated (Box 16A*)
  - Source Photos: Boxing, undated (Box 16A*)
  - Source Photos: Graffiti, undated (Box 16A*)
  - Source Photos: Chinatown & Chinese Imagery, undated (Box 17*)
  - Source Photos: Chinatown & Chinese Imagery, undated (Box 17A*)
  - Source Photos: Various, undated (Box 18*)
  - Source Photos: Prison, undated (Box 18A*)
  - Source Photos: Cops, Firefighters, Men in Uniform, undated (Box 18A*)
  - Source Photos: Works of Art & Museum Pieces, undated (Box 18A*)
  - Source Photos: Cars & Motorbikes, undated (Box 18A*)
  - Source Photos: People, undated (Box 19*)
  - Source Photos: People, undated (Box 19A*)
  - Source Photos: People, undated (Box 20*)
  - Source Photos: People, undated (Box 20A*)
  - Photo Collage: Natural History Display, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Photo Collage: Prisons, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Photo Collage: Yard Art, undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Photo Collage: Cityscapes, undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Photo Collage: Artwork, Martin Wong, undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Photo Collage: Skyline, undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Photo Collage: Fishing Boat, undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Photograph: Aaron Goodstone (Sharp); Henry Chalfant; Unidentified Person, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Photo Collage: Chinatown Buildings, undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Photo Collage: Stairwell, undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
- Series VII: Personal Library, 1939-1992; 5 Linear Feet in 5 record cartons.
  Series VII: Personal Library consists of nearly one hundred books from Wong's own personal collection, many of which served as source material for Wong's trademark images - firefighters, constellations, sign language, prison, and Chinatown, among others. Three items in this series also include drawings by Wong and by Daze on the inside cover; these items are marked with an asterisk.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by author surname, with unidentified material following.
  - Abbott, Jack Henry, with Norman Mailer. In the Belly of the Beast: Letters from Prison. New York: Random House, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Abrams, Richard I., and Warner A. Hutchinson. An Illustrated Life of Jesus: From the National Gallery Art Collection. New York: Bell Publishing, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Amadon, Alfred Mason. The Fold-Out Atlas of the Human Body: A Three Dimensional Book. New York: Bonanza Pop-Up, 1984. **NOTE: Pen & ink sign language and brick drawing by Wong, in front cover** (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Amiel, Leon, Ed. The San Francisco I Love. New York: Tudor Publishing, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Amnesty International. Torture in the Eighties: An Amnesty International Report. London: Amnesty International Publications, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Bannerman, Helen. The Story of Little Black Sambo. New York: Platt & Munk, [n.d.], undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Beijing Summer Palace Administrative Office and the Department of Architecture of Qinghua University. Summer Palace. Beijing: Zhaohua Publishing House, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Berger, Melvin. Early Humans: A Prehistoric World. A Pop-Up Book. New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 7A)
  - Bernstein, Barry. Literature and Language: American Literature. Evanston, IL: McDougal, Littell, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Bertinetti, Marcello and Angela Bertinetti. San Francisco. New York: Gallery Books, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Betti, Silvio, Ed. Africa: Project Against Apartheid. Istituto Europeo di Design: 1988/89, 1988, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Boullet, Jean. Bizarre: La Galerie des Monstres. Paris: Societe pour la Creation et la Diffusion des Livres, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 10A)
  - Brown, Margaret Wise, and Edith Thacher Hurd. Five Little Firemen. New York: Simon & Schuster, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Cameron, Robert, and Robert E. Burger. Robert Cameron's Alcatraz: A Visual Essay. San Francisco: Cameron and Co., 1989 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Camhi, Morrie. The Prison Experience: Photography. Rutland, VT: Charles E. Tuttle, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Carraher, Ronald G. Artists in Spite of Art. New York: Van Nostrand Reinhold, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Champlin, Charles. George Lucas: The Creative Impulse (The Star Wars Trilogy Collector's Edition). New York: Harry N. Abrams, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Chase, Alice Elizabeth. Famous Paintings: An Introduction to Art for Young People. New York: Platt and Munk, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Coleman, Joe. The Mystery of Wolverine Woo-Bait. New York: Joe Coleman, 1982. [OVERSIZE: in Box 25] (Box 21, Folder 16A)
  - Colman, Elizabeth. Chinatown U.S.A. New York: John Day, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Davidson, R. Theodore. Chicano Prisoners: The Key to San Quentin. New York: Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Davies, Nancy Millichap. San Francisco. New York: Gallery Books, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Deluca, Chuck. Firehouse Memorabilia: A Collector's Reference. York, ME: Maritime Antique Auctions, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - DeNevi, Don. Alcatraz '46: The Anatomy of a Classic Prison Tragedy. San Rafael, CA: Leswing Press, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Drimmer, Frederick. Until You Are Dead.: The Book of Executions in America. New York: Windsor, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Du Bois, William Pene. The Forbidden Forest. New York: Harper & Row, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Duggan, Moira. New York City. New York: Gallery Books, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - F. Rolin & Co. African Ivories. New York: F. Rolin & Co., 1978 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Flying Saucer News. Flying Saucers: An Analysis of the Air Force Project Blue Book Special Report No. 14. New York: Flying Saucer News, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Flying Saucers from Other Worlds. Oct 1957. Evanston, IL: Palmer Publications (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Freed, Leonard. New York Police. Paris: Centre Nationale de la Photographie, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Gelman, Woody, and Barbara Jackson. Disaster Illustrated: Two Hundred Years of American Misfortune. New York: Harmony Books, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Genthe, Arnold, and John Kuo Wei Tchen. Genthe's Photographs of San Francisco's Old Chinatown. New York: Dover, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Gibbon, Dave, Ted Smart, and Edmund Nagele. San Francisco: A Picture Book to Remember Her By. New York: Crescent, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Gnagy, Jon. Learn to Draw With Jon Gnagy. [1945?] (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Gross, Steve, and Susan Daley. Old Houses. New York: Stewart, Tabori & Chang, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Hall, Douglas Kent. In Prison. New York: Henry Holt, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Hall, George N., and Thomas K. Wanstall. FDNY: New York's Bravest. San Francisco: Chronicle Books, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Hall, George N., and Thomas K. Wanstall. FDNY: New York's Bravest. Mill Valley, CA: Squarebooks, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Harris, Bill, with Louise Houghton. California: A Picture Memory. New York: Crescent Books, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Haycox, Ernest. Man in the Saddle. New York: Triangle Books, 1941 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Hibbert, Christopher. Versailles. New York: Newsweek, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Hoefer, Hans. Stoned Images. New York: E.P. Dutton, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Hogg, Ian V., John Weeks, and Joseph J. Schroeder. Pistols of the World. Northfield, IL: DBI Books, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Hollander, Zander. The Complete Handbook of Pro Hockey: 1980 Season. New York: Signet, 1979. **NOTE: Pen & ink drawing of weeping Christ figure by Wong, in front cover** (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - Important Chinese Ceramics From the J. M. Hu Family Collection. New York: Sotheby's, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - Johnson, Paul C., Ed. Beautiful California. Menlo Park, CA: Lane, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 44)
  - Karp, Walter. The Smithsonian Institution. Washington: The Smithsonian Institution, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 45)
  - Katsui, Mitsuo, and Toshifumi Kawahara, Eds. World Graphic Design Now: Computer Graphics. Tokyo: Kodansha, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 46)
  - Klepsch, Marvin, and Laura Logie. Children Draw and Tell: An Introduction to the Projective Uses of Children's Human Figure Drawings. New York: Brunner/Mazel, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 47)
  - Krell, Dorothy, Ed. Beautiful California. Menlo Park, CA: Lane, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 48)
  - La Venus de Milo [Chinese language text], undated (Box 23, Folder 49)
  - Liberty: A Centennial History of the Statue of Liberty in Post Cards. New York: Madison Square Press, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 50)
  - Liu, Lawrence G. Chinese Architecture. New York: Rizzoli, 1989. (Box 23, Folder 51)
    Graffiti art by Daze on front cover.
  - Liu, Lawrence. Chinese Architecture. New York: Rizzoli, 1989. (Box 25, Folder 51)
  - Loyd, Chuck. The Gang Rape. New York: Spade Classics, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 52)
  - Lynch, Edie. With Glory I So Humbly Stand. New York: Vantage, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 53)
  - Maass, Robert. Fire Fighters. New York: Scholastic, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 54)
  - Madigan, Paul J. Institution Rules and Regulations, United States Penitentiary, Alcatraz, California. [no publ. Information], undated (Box 23, Folder 55)
  - Manas, John H. Flying Saucers and Space Men: A Scientific and Metaphysical Dissertation in Interplanetary Traveling. New York: Pythagorean Society, 196-? (Box 23, Folder 56)
  - Mattern, Jimmie. Cloud Country, Book Two: Hawaii to Hollywood. Pure Oil Company, 1936 (Box 23, Folder 57)
  - Mauricheau-Beaupre, Charles. Versailles. Monaco: Les Documents d'Art, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 58)
  - Mauskopf, Norman. Dark Horses. Altadena, CA: Twin Palms Publishers, [n.d.], undated (Box 23, Folder 59)
  - McCarty, Cara. Information Art: Diagramming Microchips. New York: Harry N. Abrams, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 60)
  - McDowell, Jack, Ed. San Francisco. Menlo Park, CA: Lane, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 61)
  - McNally, Tom. Fishing for Boys. Chicago: Follett, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 62)
  - Merchants Association of New York. New York the Wonder City. Chicago: Curt Teich, 1939 (Box 24, Folder 63)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art. The Unicorn Tapestries at the Cloisters. New York: Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 64)
  - Miller, H. Tatlock, and Loudon Sainthill. Undoubted Queen. New York: Doubleday, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 65)
  - Mitchell, Lucy Sprague, Irma Simonton Black, and Jessie Stanton. The Taxi That Hurried. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1946 (Box 24, Folder 66)
  - Mitchell, Lucy Sprague. A Year in the City. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 67)
  - Monkhouse, Richard, and John Cox. 3-D Star Maps. New York: Harper & Row, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 68)
  - Moorhouse, Geoffrey. The Great Cities: San Francisco. Amsterdam: Time-Life Books, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 69)
  - Navy Exchange Photographic Services Center. The Keel: Recruit Training Command. Great Lakes, IL: Walsworth Publishing, [n.d.], undated (Box 24, Folder 70)
  - New York State Special Commission on Attica. Attica: The Official Report of the New York State Special Commission on Attica. New York: Bantam, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 71)
  - Obenzinger, Hilton. New York on Fire. Seattle: Real Comet Press, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 72)
  - Page, Lou Williams. A Dipper Full of Stars: A Beginner's Guide to the Heavens. Sacramento: California State Department of Education, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 73)
  - Peery, Rex, and Arnold "Swede" Umbach. Wrestling. New York: Sterling, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 74)
  - Perkins, D. M. Deep Throat. New York: Dell, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 75)
  - Perkins, Peter, and Richard Reinhardt. Chinatown, San Francisco. Berkeley: Lancaster-Miller, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 76)
  - Pienkowski, Jan. Robot. New York: Delacorte, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 76A)
  - Preston, Andrew. San Francisco: A Picture Memory. New York: Crescent Books, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 77)
  - Rasmussen, Henry. Fire Trucks: American Fire Fighters on the Street. Osceola, WI: Motorbooks International, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 78)
  - Reed, Eli, and Fouad Ajami. Beirut: City of Regrets. New York: W.W. Norton, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 79)
  - Ridpath, Ian, Ed. The Illustrated Encyclopedia of Astronomy and Space. New York: Thomas Y. Crowell, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 80)
  - Riekehof, Lottie L. The Joy of Signing: The Illustrated Guide for Mastering Sign Language and the Manual Alphabet. Springfield, MO: Gospel, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 81)
  - Smith, Dennis, and Jill Freedman. Firehouse. New York: Doubleday, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 82)
  - Sotheby Parke Bernet Inc. Fine Oriental Miniatures, Manuscripts and Islamic Works of Art Including the Fraser Album. New York: Sotheby Parke Bernet, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 83)
  - Sotheby's. Contemporary Art, Part I. New York: Sotheby's, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 84)
  - Spooner, Peter, et. al. BIOkinetic. Normal, IL: Illinois State University, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 85)
  - Stephen, R.J. Fire Engines. New York: Franklin Watts, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 86)
  - Swinglehurst, Edmund. San Francisco. New York: Mayflower Books, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 87)
  - Tanizaki, Junichiro. In Praise of Shadows. Trans. Thomas J. Harper and Edward G. Seidensticker. New Haven: Leete's Island Books, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 88)
  - Toda Granada. Barcelona: Escudo de Oro, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 89)
  - Viktor IV. XXXX IV Logbook Pages. Copenhagen: Brondum, 198-?, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 89A)
  - Yim, S. Y., Ed. A Century of Cantonese Opera. Hong Kong: The Regional Council, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 90)
  - Unidentifiable movie script: "Fade in: Ext. - Old City of Jerusalem.", undated (Box 25, Folder 91)
  - Chinese-language texts (2), undated (Box 25, Folder 92)
  - Library List of Wong Personal Library **prior to processing**, undated (Box 25, Folder 93)
- Series VIII: Albums, 1989; .25 Linear Feet in one half manuscript box.
  Series VIII: Albums consists of a photo album of the opening of the Museum of American Graffiti containing clippings, ephemera, and photographs of the museum and the opening celebration. A number of photographs include identification labels created by Wong of individuals at the event, including a number of graffiti artists.
  - Album: 1989 Grafffiti Museum Opening (Box 26)
    Album contains clippings, ephemera from the Museum of American Graffiti, and photographs of the Museum and the opening celebration. Individuals identified by Martin Wong in the photographs include: Kies, Spider, Ken Gonzalez Day, Robert Lee (of Asian Arts Institute), Peter Broda, Martin Wong, Wicked Gary, Lazar, Quik, Seen, Mico, Dorothy Desir-Davis, Lady Pink, Theresa Herron, Gil, Lee, Henry Chalfant, Delores Newman, Jack Stuart, Yasmin Ramires Harwood, Parents of Martin Wong, Parents of Peter Broda, Sharp, Sane, Scam, Ven, Stash, Luster, Dom, Futura, Mrs. Futura, A1,Koor, Vulcan, Part, Kool, Joey, Crash, Shaker, Zepher, Chino, Brim, Bio, Rick Prol, Dondi, Mare, Mico, Ezo, Haze, Delta, Cavs, and Charlie Ahearn.
- Series IX: Tax Receipts, 1983-1996; .25 Linear Feet in one half manuscript box.
  This series consists of tax receipts for graffiti purchases, added to the collection as an accretion in 2013.
  - Tax Receipts, Graffiti Purchases, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Tax Receipts, Graffiti Purchases, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Tax Receipts, Graffiti Purchases, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Tax Receipts, Graffiti Purchases, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Tax Receipts, Graffiti Purchases, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Tax Receipts, Graffiti Purchases, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Tax Receipts, Graffiti Purchases, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Tax Receipts, Graffiti Purchases, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Tax Receipts, Graffiti Purchases, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Tax Receipts, Graffiti Purchases, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Tax Receipts, Graffiti Purchases, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Tax Receipts, Graffiti Purchases, 1994, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 12)